-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
校对: 浅陷夜蓝 影子
翻译: 雷丘 滢小歪 咳嗽的小鱼
超体
十亿年前 我们被赐予了生命
Life was given to us a billion years ago.
我们用它做了什么?
What have we done with it?
露西?
Lucy?
就小事一桩 进去就出来 一切都准备就绪了
It's as easy as pie. In and out, all done and dusted.
那你为什么不自己去办?
Then why don't do it yourself?
那家伙绝对想不到会有个大美女来给他送手提箱
The last thing the guy is expecting is a total 10 turning up to deliver the case.
你会让他大吃一惊的 来吧
You'll blow his mind. Come on.
这里面是什么东西?
What's in it?
小甜心...
Sweetheart...
别疑神疑鬼的好吗? 你相信我 不是吗?
Don't get paranoid on me, alright? You trust me, don't you?
理查德 我是很喜欢你 可是...
Richard, I really do like you but...
我现在得先照顾好自己 我有个...
I've to take care of myself right now, I got a...
我也不知道 我有好多事得操心
I don't know, I gotta concentrate on so many things.
嘿! 嘿! 你上哪去?
Hey! Hey! What are you doing?
我回家啊 星期一我有考试
I'm going home because I have exams on Monday.
我得洗个澡 还得复习 好吗?
I have to shower and I have to study, OK?
你知道吗? 前几天我在博物馆里的时候学到了什么?
You know what? The other day I was in this museum and you know what I found out?
什么?
What?
世上第一个女人的名字就叫露西
The first ever woman was named Lucy.
露西
你以为这能让我心情好一点吗?
Is that suppose to make me feel better?
是啊...
Yeah...
- 不是  - 我会联络你的 好吗?
- No.  - I'll call you, OK?
行! 行! 行!
OK! OK! OK!
我跟你说实话吧 我没法亲自送箱子
I'll be honest with you. I can't deliver the case myself.
我和这家伙之前谈崩了 不是什么大事...
I've a little falling out with the guy. It's nothing major...
可是要是你送的话 问题就解决了
but if it's you, problem solved.
你走进去 到前台
You walk in there, you go up to the reception,
让他叫张先生下来
you ask Mr. Jang to come down.
他下来 拿走手提箱 你给他闪个你最迷人的笑容 然后走人
He comes down, he takes the case, you flash him your prettiest smile and bounce.
你看 前台从这里都能看得见
Look, you can even see the reception from here.
拜托
Come on.
- 箱子里到底是什么?  - 不知道 就一堆文件
- What's in the case?  - I don't know, it's just some paperwork.
- 是吗? 那让咱看看  - 锁着呢
- Yeah? Let's see it then.  - It's locked
除了张先生以外没人有密码
and no one but Mr. Jang has the code.
我就是个送信人
I'm just the delivery boy.
- 你这么做有钱赚吗?  - 啊 算是吧
- Do you get paid to do this?  - Yeah, kinda.
大概给多少?
Like how much?
现在是在谈价钱了还是...?
OK, we're negotiating now or ...?
不是 不是 你能赚多钱? 我想知道 多少?
No, no, how much do you get paid? I want to know, how much?
一千美元
A thousand dollars.
给你一千美金让你送点文件 真的假的?
You get paid a thousand dollars for delivering paperwork, really?
我不知道 总之只用我十分钟 他们就付我一千块 剩下的不关我的事
I don't know, it takes me 10 minutes and they're paying a grand and the rest is none of my business.
好啊 也不关我什么事 我跟你说...
Well, it's not my business either. I'll tell you now...
- 听我说!  - 干嘛?
- Listen!  - What?
我们五五平分
We split it down the middle.
你五百 我五百
That's 500 for you and 500 for me.
- 理查德 我会打电话给你的  - 听我说! 这礼拜我已经三次
- Richard, I will call you.  - Listen! It is the third time this week
出现在同一个酒店 戴着同一顶牛仔帽
I'm showing up at the same hotel with the same cowboy hat.
问题解决啦
Problem solved.
- 去吧! 去吧! 我会等着你的  - 露西 宝贝
- Go! Go! I'll wait for you to go.  - Lucy, honey,
我... 这活我已经做过十几次了
I... I've done this a dozen times.
只是文件! 可能就是他们为了仿造而偷来的一些设计图
It's paperwork! It's probably just some designs they swept so they can copy them.
这国家就是这样
That's how it works in this country.
就连我的斯泰森牛仔帽也是从这产的 你看!
Even my Stetson was made here. Look!
标签上写着呢: "台湾制造"
It says so on the label: "Made in Taiwan"
再会了 戴着冒牌斯泰森牛仔帽的牛仔
So long, cowboy, with a fake Stetson.
宝贝 求你了!
Baby, please!
理查德 我得走了
Richard, I gotta go.
- 你干嘛呢?  - 很抱歉
- What the hell are you doing?  - I'm sorry.
- 你到底干...  - 非常抱歉 我是真的需要你的帮助
- What the hell are you do...  - I'm so sorry. I really need your help.
打住! 打住! 马上给我摘下来!
Stop it! Stop it! Take this off me, right now!
- 我没办法!  - 马上给我摘下来!
- I can't!  - Take this off me, right now!
- 我没办法! 张先生是唯一有钥匙的人!  - 不行!
- I can't! Mr. Jang is the only one who has the key!  - No!
你只需要走进酒店里面 跟前台说你要找他
All you have to is go into the hotel and ask for him at the reception.
不行! 马上给我摘下来!
No! Take it off me, right now!
真对不起 我真的别无选择 你越快进去就越快出来
I'm so sorry, I really have no choice. The sooner you go in, the sooner you'll be back out.
我真不敢相信你会这么对我
I can't believe you did this to me.
- 我在这一动不动 我向你保证  - 你的保证连个屁都不值!
- I'll be right here, you have my word.  - Your word isn't worth shit!
呃... 值五百块 提前支付
Uh... it's worth 500 bucks, upfront.
你真是个王八蛋!
You're an asshole!
你真是棒极了 对不?
And you're wonderful, huh?
小姐 我能为你效劳吗?
Miss, may I help you?
是的
Yes.
我想要找 呃...
I'm here for, uh...
张先生
Mr. Jang.
好
Yes.
我应该说是谁要找他?
Who should I say is here?
理查德
Richard.
呃... 不对... 理查德叫我... 理查德叫我来的
Uhm... no... Richard sent... Richard sent me.
你叫什么?
What is your name?
不是 是理查德
No, Richard.
理查德... 呃... 他在找停车位
Richard's... uh... he's just looking for a place to park.
张先生还是想知道你的名字
Mr. Jang still wants to know your name.
露西
Lucy.
露西什么?
Lucy what?
就是露西 他要是能... 要是能快点的话 因为我得... 我得...
Just Lucy. If he could... If he could he quick 'cause I have... I have to...
先等我翻译一下...
Just a second while I translate...
张先生马上下来 待在这别动
Mr. Jang is on his way, stay right here.
我能坐下吗?
Can I sit?
张先生让你待在这别动 我觉得你最好待在这别动
Mr. Jang said you need to stay right here. I think it's better if you stay right here.
不好意思 皇家酒店
Excuse me. Regent Hotel.
不要!
No!
不要 等等! 不要啊!
No, wait! No!
求你们了!
Please!
等一下 我什么都不知道!
Wait, I don't know anything!
我什么都不知道! 求求你! 求求你!
I don't know anything! Please! Please!
不要 求求你!
No, please!
您会说英语吗?
Do you speak English?
我也会说一点西班牙语
Tambien hablo poco Espanol.
露西 对 我是露西
Lucy, yes, I'm Lucy.
其实就是天大的误解 我只是来送这个手提箱的
It's just been a terrible mistake. I'm just suppose to deliver this case.
您钥匙要是丢了 不需要切我的手 切锁链就行 好吗?
If you lost the key, you don't have to chop off my hand, you can just cut the chain, OK?
求求你!
Please!
我求您了 拜托了!
I'm begging you, please!
不要! 不要! 不要呀!
No! No! No!
不要! 不要! 求求你!
No! No! Please!
求求你!
Please!
小姐您好 我会说英语 我为张先生做翻译
Hello, Miss, I speak English. I translate for Mr. Jang.
请你告诉他 我什么都没做 我什么都不知道
Please tell him that I haven't done anything. I don't know anything.
这整个就是个天大的误解 好吗? 请你跟他说
It's all just a big mistake, OK? Please, please tell him that.
好 可以 稍等
Yes, OK, OK, hold on.
张先生想知道箱子里装的是什么
Mr. Jang wants to know what's in the case.
我不知道里面是什么 你到底会不会说英语?!
Well, I don't know what's in the case. Do you speak English or don't you speak English?!
我会! 我在纽约的一所国际高中里读过一年书
Yes, I do! I studied one year at International High School in New York.
好
OK.
理查德让我把这个箱子给你 我只知道这些
Richard gave me the case to give to you, that's all I know.
好 请你告诉他
OK, please tell him that.
他给了我一张写了数字的纸 我不... 这是什么?
He gave me a paper with numbers written on it, I don't... what is this?
是开箱的密码
It's the code to open the case.
这里面究竟是什么?
What's really in here?
不是危险的东西
Nothing dangerous.
那他怎么不自己开?
So why won't he open it himself?
他不信任理查德先生
He doesn't trust Mr. Richard.
我也不信任理查德
I don't trust Richard either.
我只和他谈了一星期的恋爱
I only dated him for a week.
行! 行! 行!
OK! OK! OK!
- 张先生执意要你打开箱子  - 行! 行!
- Mr. Jang insists that you open the case.  - OK! OK!
上帝啊 救救我
Please God, help me.
他让你利索点 张先生还有要事缠身
He wants you to hurry up, Mr. Jang has other things to do.
你可不可以描述一下箱子里的东西?
Can you describe the content of the case?
是四个塑料袋 里面装着蓝色的粉末像是...
It's 4 plastic pouches filled with blue powder like a...
或许是紫色的粉末? 我不知道 看起来挺恶心
or maybe a purple powder? I don't know, it looks gross.
张先生想给你一份工作
Mr. Jang wants to offer you a job.
工作?
A job?
我不想要工作!
I don't want a job!
生命起源于大约十亿年前
If life starts approximately a billion years ago,
我们得在四十万年后
we'll have to wait 400,000 years
才能看到第一波神经细胞演变出来
to see the aberration of the first nerve cells.
这就是我们说的生命的起点
This is where life we know it begins.
从这些只有几毫米长的脑组织中
Brains in formation of only a few milligrams
我们无法断定 是否有智慧的存在
is not possible to determine any sign of intelligence yet.
它表现得更像反射作用
It acts more as a reflex.
一颗脑细胞 你活着 两颗脑细胞 你动着
One neuron, you're alive. Two neurons, you're moving.
而一旦有了活动 就会出现有趣的事情
And with movement, interesting things begin to happen.
数百万年前地球上就出现了动物
Animal life on Earth goes back millions of years.
然而 大多数物种只使用了大脑的百分之三到五
Yet, most species only use 3-5% of its cerebral capacity.
可是 只有成为人类 达食物链顶端的时候
But it isn't until we reached human beings at the top of the animal chain,
我们才终于发现一种物种更多地使用了其脑容量
that we finally see a species used more of its cerebral capacity.
百分之十看似不多 但要是从人类用它所做的一切来看 已经很多了
10% may not seem like much but it's a lot if we look at all we've done with it.
现在我们来谈论一个特例
Now let's discuss a special case.
唯一一种比我们更好地利用大脑的生物...
The only living being that uses its brain better than us...
海豚
the dolphin.
据估计 这种不可思议的动物
It's estimated that this incredible animal
可以利用到大脑的百分之二十
uses up to 20% of its cerebral capacity.
尤其在于 这使它拥有着一种回声定位系统
And in particular, this allows it to have an echo-location system
比任何人类所发明的声纳系统都更加有效
that's more efficient than any sonar invented by mankind.
但是海豚并没有发明声纳 它是自然形成的
But the dolphin did not invent the sonar. It developed it naturally.
而这就是我们今天的哲学探讨中
And this is the crucial part of our
最具有关键性的环节
philosophical reflection we have today.
我们是否能够得出这样的结论
Can we therefore conclude
即人类更在意
that humans are concerned more with
"拥有"
"having"
而不是"具有"
than "being".
露西
Lucy.
你对我的腹部做了些什么?
What did you do with my stomach?
没什么! 只是一个小小的水平切口 刀工非常利落
Nothing! Just a little horizontal slit. It's very well done
一个月之后你会看到 疤痕基本就消失了
and you'll find that in a month, this scar is practically invisible too.
明年夏天你就能去海滩秀你的小蛮腰了
You'll be able to show your tummy off on the beach next summer.
我不在乎有没有疤
I don't care about the scar.
是不是 呃... 是不是我们为什么给你开刀?
Is it, uh... is it why we opened you up?
你放心 我们没有取你的器官什么的
Rest assured, we didn't harvest your organs or anything.
我们只是在你小腹里面放了个小包裹
Uh, we merely slipped a little package in your lower tummy.
它是... 一种新毒品 欧洲的孩子们会爱上它的 相信我
It's a... it's a new drug the kids in Europe are gonna love, believe me.
- 到底是什么?  - 学名叫做CPH4
- What is it?  - Well, the scientific term is CPH4,
从销售方面来看名字的确不是很诱人
which is not very sexy from a sale's point of view.
所以呃... 我们... 我们还在想时髦一点的名字...
So, uh... we're... we're still working on something a little bit more pop...
你有没有建议?
Any suggestions?
请稍等
Excuse me.
欢迎
Welcome.
欢迎 请进 很好 哎呦...
Welcome, come on in. Lovely, oops...
很不错! 很不错!
Splendid! Splendid!
真是不可思议! 很好很好!
Marvelous! Lovely lovely!
- 你还好吗?  - 我很好 亲爱的
- How are you?  - Very good, my dear.
好
OK.
这个 呃... 首先 非常感谢各位参与此次的计划
Right, uh... first of all, many thanks for taking part in this enterprise
我相信一定会完美完成任务
which I'm sure will go off flawlessly.
这些护照和机票呢
These lovely passport and tickets
可以让你在接下来的二十四小时内重返家园
will enable you to return home in the next 24 hours.
那么 当你到达的时候 会有我们的人接应你
Now, upon arrival, you'll be taken in hand by our people
这样我们才可以收回我们的货
so that we might recover our merchandise
而你们则可以重新获得那千辛万苦挣来的自由
and you might re-discover the freedom which you so richly deserve.
相信你们无需提醒 不过你们之中那些试图
I'm sure I don't need to remind you but, for any of those who may be tempted to
警告或者把自己交给警方的人呢
warn or turn themselves in to the authorities,
我们手上有你所有家属的姓名和住址 包括你的三姑六婆八大爷
we have the names and addresses of the families of every one of you down to the distant cousins.
所以我们相信你们会慎重行事
So, we rely therefore, on your complete discretion.
很好 那么 呃...
Good, anyway, uh...
先生们 和女士 请让我作为第一个祝福你们的人
gentleman, madam, allow me to be the first to wish you
一路顺风!
bon voyage!
哎呦!
Oops!
你们要卖这东西?
You gonna sell this?
恐怕这就是我们的商业模式
I'm afraid it's our business model.
对于我们这种原始生物来说 生命似乎只有一个目的
For primitive beings like us, life seems to only have one single purpose.
获得时间
Gaining time.
而花费时间 似乎也正是
And its going through time, seems to be also the only
我们体内每个细胞的真正和唯一的目的
real purpose of each of the cell in our bodies.
为了达到这个目标 那堆
To achieve that aim, the mass of the cells
能组成包括蚯蚓和人类的细胞
that make up earthworm and human beings
只有两种方法
has only 2 solutions:
长生不老...
be immortal...
或是繁衍后代
or to reproduce.
若它们的栖息之地不适合繁殖后代
If its habitat is not sufficiently favourable or nurturing,
细胞则会选择长生不老
the cell will choose immortality.
换句话说 自给自足以及自主管理
In other words, self-sufficiency and self-management.
另一方面 若栖息之地及其有利
On the other hand, if the habitat is favourable,
它们会选择繁殖
they will choose to reproduce.
这样一来 它们死的时候
That way, when they die,
会传递必要的信息和知识给下一个细胞
they hand down essential information and knowledge to the next cell
然后再传递给下一个细胞 以此类推
which hands it down to the next cell and so on.
因此 知识和学问
Thus, knowledge and learning
都是通过时间而传承的
are handed down through time.
好 好 保持冷静...
OK, OK, keep calm...
你必须等待 拖延时间
You have to wait, just play for time...
在飞机上你会有时间想办法的... 先上飞机
You'll have time to think it through on the plane... just take the flight,
先上飞机 离开这里
take the flight, get out of here.
这是最主要的 争取时间
That's the main thing right now, just save time.
什么都别干 保持冷静 你还活着...
Don't try anything, keep your cool, you're alive...
你还活着... 你还活着 只有这是重要的
you're alive... you're alive, that's all that matters.
等待 争取时间
Just wait, save time.
争取时间
Save time.
老娘我没心情
I'm not in the mood.
我们稍微设想一下
Let's imagine for a few moments
要是可以启用我们大脑的百分之二十的话
what our life would be like if we could access, let's say,
我们的生命会是什么样子
20 % of our brains' capacity.
这第一阶段会使我们能够了解并控制
This first stage would give us access to and control
我们的身体
of our own body.
- 先生  - 请说?
- Sir.  - Yes?
这被科学证实了吗?
Has it been proven scientifically?
哦 目前来说 我承认这只是假设
Oh, for the moment, it's just hypothesis, I confess.
但是你想想看
But if you think about it,
早在显微镜被发明几百年前 古埃及人 古希腊人和古印度人
it's troubling to realize that the Greeks, the Egyptians and the Indians
就意识到了"细胞"的存在 这是个让人不安的事实
had notion of "cells" centuries before the invention of the microscope.
再看看达尔文
And what to say about Darwin
当他提出进化论的时候 他遭到了所有人的嘲笑
whom everybody took for a fool when he put forward his Theory of Evolution.
如今需要我们来有所突破
It's up to us to push the rules and laws
从"进化"走向"革命"
and go from "evolution" to "revolution".
平均每人有一千亿个神经元
100 billion neurons per human,
其中被运用的只有15%
of which only 15% are activated.
人体内各部分之间的联系比银河中的恒星还要多
There're more connections in the human body than there're stars in the galaxy.
我们拥有一个无比庞大的信息网络
We possess a gigantic network of information
但是我们对它仍几乎一无所知
to which we've almost no access.
- 先生!  - 请说?
- Sir!  - Yes?
那下一阶段呢?
And what would be the next stage?
嗯 在下一阶段很可能会是控制他人
Well, the next stage would probably be control of other people.
但是要做到这一点 我们需要至少能使用大脑的百分之四十
But for that, we will need to access at least 40% of our brains' capacity.
在能控制自己和他人之后
And after control of ourselves and others,
就是控制物质
come control of matter.
但是这就完全是科幻小说了
But now we're entering the realm of science fiction.
对此 我们就像是犬狗望月一样一无所知
And we don't know anything more than a dog who watches the moon.
- 打扰下 先生  - 请说
- Excuse me, sir.  - Yes.
如果有人能使用其大脑百分之百的能力
But what would happen if for some reason we ignore
那会是怎样的?
somebody unlock 100% of the celebral capacity?
百分之百吗?
100%?
是的
Yes.
我真不知道
I've no idea.
嘿!
Hey!
- 嘿 你会说英语吗?  - 不 不 不
- Hey, you speak English?  - No. No. No.
- 你会说英语吗?  - 会 会
- You speak English? - Yes. Yes.
- 马上送我去医院  - 医院?
- Take me to the hospital now.  - Hospital?
我的腿!
- 医院  - 在这等我
- Hospital.  - Wait for me.
小姐 你好?
Miss, hello?
嘿 小姐!
Hey, miss!
我需要帮助 很紧急
I need help, it's urgent.
你不能进来 我们在做手术
You cannot be in here. We're operating.
请你出去!
Please, get out!
你们根本救不了他
You wouldn't be able to save him anyway.
肿瘤已经长到了他的大脑皮层和脊柱右侧
Tumour already invaded the cortext and right side of his spine.
有人在我身体里放了一袋毒品 我要你把它拿出来
Somebody put a bag of drug in me. I need you to remove it.
它漏了
It's leaking.
现在就做
Do it now.
好 我先给你局部麻醉...
Right. I'll just administer local anaethestic...
不用了
Don't bother.
好吧 我.... 好的
Right, I... okay.
请冷静下 把枪放下来
Calm down, please. Put the gun down.
我先... 检查一下 好吗?
I'm just going to... examine, OK?
- 介意我用一下吗?  - 不介意
- Do you mind?  - No.
- 你好?  - 妈?
- Hello?  - Mom?
嘿 露西
Hey, Lucy.
宝贝 你打电话来我真开心
Baby, it's great to hear from you
你那里现在是几点?
but what time is it over there?
我不知道 是晚上了
I don't know. It's night.
等一下 先让我把另一通电话挂了
Hold on a sec', let me get rid of the other line.
我要开始取了
I'm going to go inside.
我回来了 你没有成天出去聚会吧?
I'm back, you're not partying too much, are you?
你答应过我会照顾好自己
You promised me you'll look after yourself.
我努力 妈妈 我努力
I'm trying to, Mommy, I'm trying to.
好吧 谢谢你能意外地打电话回来
Well, thanks for calling out of the blue like this.
你父亲错过了你的电话 肯定很难过
Your father is gonna be sad he missed you.
他去了健身房还没回来 你一般都是早上打给我们
He isn't home from the gym yet. Usually you call us in the morning.
- 妈...  - 嗯?
- Mom...  - Yes?
我感受到了一切
I feel everything.
你说什么 亲爱的?
What do you mean, sweatie?
空间
Space,
空气
the air,
振动
the vibrations,
还有人
the people.
我能感觉到重力
I can feel the gravity.
我能感觉到地球的转动
I can feel the rotation of the Earth.
身体的热量在消失
The heat leaving my body,
血管里的血液在流动
the blood in my veins,
我能感受到我的大脑
I can feel my brain.
我记忆的最深处
The deepest parts of my memory.
亲爱的 信号不好 我听不太清你在说什么
Sweatie, we've a bad connection, I can't hear you so well.
你说"记忆"怎么了?
What did you say about "memory"?
当我带上牙箍时 嘴里的疼痛 我...
The pain in my mouth, when I had braces, I ...
我记起我发烧时 你手摸我额头的感觉
I can remember the feeling of your hand on my forehead when I ran a fever.
我记得摸到猫的感觉 它真的很软
I remember stroking the cat. It was so soft.
猫? 什么猫 宝贝?
A cat? What cat, honey?
蓝眼睛 断了尾巴的那只暹罗猫
Siamese with blue eye and a broken tail.
亲爱的 你不可能还记得啊
Sweatie, you can't possibly remember that.
你那时候只有一岁大
You were barely a year old.
我记得吃奶的日子
I remember the days of your milk in my mouth,
那个房间
the room,
乳汁...
the liquid...
亲爱的 你在说些什么啊?
Sweatie, what are you talking about?
我想告诉你我爱你们 爸妈...
I just wanna tell you that I love you, Mom and Dad...
亲爱的...
Sweatie...
我想谢谢你们 因为...
And I wanna thank you for the...
你们无数次吻在我脸上的感觉我仍感受得到...
thousand kisses that I can still feel on my face...
我爱你 妈
I love you, Mom.
我也爱你 亲爱的
I love you too, sweatie,
胜过世间任何东西
more than anything in the world.
还剩多少?
How much is left?
五百克?
500 grams?
我身体还需要多少时间把其余的代谢掉?
And how long will it take for my body to eliminate the rest of it?
要回答这个问题 我得知道这是什么
To answer that, I need to know what it is.
可以吗?
May I?
继续吧
Go ahead.
是CPH4
CPH4.
告诉我
Tell me about it.
孕妇会在怀孕第六周的时候
Pregnant women manufacture CPH4 in the sixth week of pregnancy,
分泌微量的CPH4
in tiny quantities.
这给婴儿带来了相当于一颗原子弹的能量
For a baby, it packs the power of an atomic bomb.
这是胎儿生成骨骼结构所必需的能量
It's what gives the foetus the necessary energy to form all the bones in its body.
我听说有人试图人工合成
I've heard they tried to make a synthetic version of it.
没想到他们成功了
Didn't realize that they succeeded.
如果这真是CPH4
If it really is CPH4,
以这个量来说 我真惊讶你竟然还活着
in this quantity, I'm amazed you're still alive.
活不了多久
Not for long.
学习总是痛苦的
Learning is always a painful process.
就像你小的时候 你会因骨骼生长而全身疼痛
Like when you're little, your bones are growing and you ached all over.
你相信我能记得自己骨骼生长的声音吗?
Can you believe I can remember the sound of my own bones growing?
像这皮肤下磨得吱吱的声音
Like this grinding under the skin.
现在一切都不一样了
Everything is different now.
就比如... 我能理解音乐 就像流水...
Like... sound of music that I can understand, like fluids...
有趣的是我曾经满脑子想着
It's funny I used to be so concerned with
我是谁 我要成为什么样的人 还有...
who I was and what I wanted to be, and...
现在我能感受到我脑海的最深处 我看待事情清晰了 也明白了
now I've access to the furthest reaches of my brain, I see things clearly and realize
"我们"成为如今这样是有其原始原因的
what make us "us", it's primitive.
它们都是障碍物
They're all obstacles.
你能明白吗?
Does that make any sense?
就像你正在遭受的痛苦...
Like this pain you're experiencing...
它使你无法理解其它事物
is blocking you from understanding.
你知道的只有疼痛
All you know now is pain.
你只知道疼痛
That's all you know, pain.
其他人在哪里?
Where are the others?
其他带着毒品的人 我需要剩下的毒品
The others carrying the drugs. I need the rest of it
作医疗用途
for medicinal purposes.
柏林
Berlin.
巴黎
Paris.
罗马
Rome.
谢谢你的分享
Thank you for sharing.
- 晚上好 教授  - 我说过我会回来
- Oh, good evening, Professor.  - I sweared I'll be back.
你今晚没忘了用餐吧?
You hadn't forget your dinner tonight?
恐怕是的 我累坏了
I'm afraid so. I'm exhausted.
- 好好休息  - 谢谢
- Have a good rest.  - Thank you.
你吓死我了 这门敲得跟个神经病一样!
You scared the shit out of me. You ring that bell like some nut bar!
我想你啦!
I missed you!
我也是
Me too.
你丢了钥匙还是怎么?
You lose your key or something?
是啊
Yeah.
- 我能借你笔记本用下吗?  - 好的 没问题
- Can I borrow your laptop?  - Yeah, of course.
我去试镜试了一整天 太棒了
So I spent all day at this audition, awesome.
他们满口中文 就让你在那站一整天 因为他们根本就不在乎你的时间重不重要
They just have you standing around all day because they don't give a shit about your time, gabbing away in Chinese.
谁能听懂中文? 反正我是不懂
Who understand Chinese? I don't understand Chinese.
他们还说他们一定会有回信
And then they say they always gonna call
但是从不回信 他们都不记你的手机号码
and they never do. They don't even take your phone number.
你知道吧 除了一个男的 我觉着他... 他不是中国人
You know.Except this one guy, I bet he, uh...he's not Chinese.
他在那儿工作 很帅... 天啊 他真帅!
He works at the agency and he's cute... Oh my God, he's cute!
你懂的 帅得很特别 有种特殊的魅力...
You know, like, the cute in kinda way, like he has this thing...
天啊 他的屁股...
Oh my God, his ass...
我们来说说这个!
Let me get started on that!
你肯定猜不到他带我去哪里了
And you'll never gonna guess where he take me.
四季酒店 皇家套房 我们一整晚都在滚床单
Four Seasons, Royal Suite, and we made love all night.
抱歉 光顾着说我了 你呢? 理查德怎么样?
I'm sorry, I'm talking about myself. What's up? How's Richard?
他死了
He's dead.
你们真疯 我去冲个澡
You guys are crazy. I'm gonna take a shower.
- 你好?  - 诺曼教授 我的名字叫露西
- Yes?  - Profesor Norman, my name is Lucy.
我看完了你有关人脑的所有研究 我们有必要见个面
I've just read all your research on the human's brain. We need to meet.
我所有的研究?
All of my research?
真是受宠若惊 小姐 但是这让人难以置信
Well, I'm very flattered, young lady. But I find that hard to believe.
我可写了整整...
I must have written no less than...
六千七百三十四页 我可以全部背出来了
6734 pages. I can recite them too all by heart if you wish.
你是艾米丽的朋友吗?
Are you one of Emily's friends?
这听起来真像她开的玩笑 她和你在一起吗?
This sounds like one of her silly jokes. Is she there with you?
不 只有我一个人
No, I'm on my own.
- 你是谁?  - 我刚告诉过你
- Who are you?  - I just told you.
露西 是吗? 是的 抱歉
Lucy, right? Yes, sorry.
我看了你有关大脑使用的理论
I read your theory on the use of the brain's capacity.
还有些粗糙 不过方向是对的
It's a little rudimentary but you're on the right track.
哦 谢谢
Oh, thank you.
教授 我的细胞正在以惊人的速度再生
Professor, my cells are reproducing at a phenomenal speed,
每秒几百万个
several millions per second,
我也无法精确估算我剩下的寿命
and I'm having trouble precisely evaluating the time of my death
但是我觉得不会超过二十四小时
but I doubt it'll last more than 24 hours.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我是说你的理论不只是理论
What I'm saying is that your theory is not a theory.
我吸收了大量人工合成的CPH4
I absorbed a large quatity of synthetic CPH4
可以让我百分之百地运用我的大脑
that would allow me to use 100% of my celebral capacity.
现在我的使用率到了百分之二十八 你写的是事实
Right now I'm at 28% and which you wrote is true.
一旦大脑使用了百分之二十 它会整个打开
Once the brain reaches 20% , it opens up and expands the rest
不会再有阻碍
and there are no more obstacles.
就像多米诺骨牌倒下一样 我正在开拓我的大脑
They fall away like dominos. I'm colonizing my own brain.
呃... 好吧... 我不知道... 该说... 什么
Uh... well... I don't know... what to... say.
真的 我... 我研究这个理论超过二十年了 但是它...
It's true, I've... I've been working on this theory for over 20 years but it's...
它只是... 只是假设和研究想法
it's only... all ever been hypothesis and research ideas.
我... 我从没想过有人能...
I... I never thought anyone would...
你可以控制自己的新陈代谢吗?
You can control your own metabolism?
是的
Yes.
然后我开始能够控制他人的身体
And I can start to control other people's bodies.
我也能控制磁力 电波还有...
Also I can control magnetic and electric waves and...
不是全部 只是... 最基本的
not all of them, just... the most basic.
电视
Television.
电话
Telephone.
收音机
Radio.
这太神奇了
It's amazing.
我感受不到痛苦
I don't feel pain,
恐惧
fear,
欲望
desire.
就好像所有人类的特征都在慢慢消失
It's like all things that make us human are fading away.
当我越发感觉不像人类的时候
It's like the less human I feel,
所有的知识... 关于世界万物的
all these knowledge about... everything,
量子物理 应用数学
Quantum Physics, Applied Mathemathics,
细胞核的无限容量
the infinite capacity of the cell's nucleus,
它们都涌向我的大脑 所有的知识...
they're all exploding inside my brain, all these knowledge...
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do with it.
如果你是在问我... 该怎么做...
If you're asking me... what to do...
你知道...
You know...
你想想看
If you think about
生命的本源...
the very nature of life...
我的意思是 生命的最初...
I mean, from the very begining...
第一个细胞的生长... 分裂成两个细胞
The development of the first cell... divided into two cells.
生命的全部意义在于
This whole purpose of life has been
传承已有的知识
passed on what was learned.
没有更崇高的意义了
There's no higher purpose.
所以如果你问我对于你这些正在不断增长的知识 你应该怎么做 我会说
So if you're asking me what to do with all these knowledge you're accumalating, I'd say...
将它延续下去
pass it on.
就像任何一个简单的细胞一样
Just like any simple cell,
通过时间传承
going through time.
时间?
Time?
是的 当然
Yes, of course.
我会在十二小时之内到你那里
I'll be at your door in 12 hours.
- 你要走了?   - 是的
- You leaving?  - Yes.
- 这是什么?  - 一个处方
- What is this?  - A prescription.
你什么时候开始会写中文了?
Since when did you start writing Chinese?
- 一小时前  - 露西 我一个字都看不懂
- Since an hour ago.  - Lucy, I don't understand any of this.
你的肾功能不太好 你的肝脏功能也在减弱 你得改变你的生活方式
Your kidneys aren't functioning efficiently. Your liver is failing. You need to make some lifestyle changes.
吃这个药 多锻炼 吃些有机食物
Take this medication. Work out. Eat organic.
你就没问题了
You'll be OK.
昨晚十一点 一名女子枪杀了一位病人
Last night, at 11 p.m., a woman shot a patient dead.
我是德·里奥
Del Rio.
我接到一个美国公民从台湾打来的奇怪电话
一个年轻女子给我们提供了大型贩毒团伙信息
- 我来处理   - 好的 交给你了
- 你好?  - 我有关于大型贩毒团伙的重要信息
- Hello ?  - Yes, I've important imformation about a group of drug traffickers.
我要跟当局说话
I need to speak with someone in position of authority.
啊哈 你很幸运 这办公室里没人职位比我高了
Ah-hah, you're very lucky. There's no one with more authority in this office than me.
从头开始吧 你叫什么名字?
But let's start with the begining. What's your name?
听着 皮埃尔·德·里奥 离开桌子 坐回椅子上
Listen up, Pierre Del Rio, get off your desk, sit in your chair,
拿起你左手边的红色笔 记下我要说的每个字
pick up the red pen to your left and take down everything I say.
没有摄像头 快点 我没时间浪费了
There're no cameras, hurry up. I've no time to waste.
说吧
Go ahead.
有三个人即将抵达欧洲 我要告诉你他们的详细信息
I'm gonna be sending you details of three people about to arrive in Europe.
他们每人都携带了一千克毒品 我要你逮捕他们 拿到毒品
Each one is carrying a kilo of drugs. I need you to arrest them and collect the substance.
我稍后有用
I'll need it later.
什么样的毒品? 条状? 还是装在胶囊里?
What form of these drugs in? Bars? Capsules?
粉末 用塑料袋装着 藏在他们腹内
Powder, hidden in plastic pouches inside their intestines.
什么?
Excuse me?
取走的时候一定要小心 那粉末威力很大
Make sure to be careful when you remove them. The product is very powerful.
相信我
Believe me.
看到了吗?
Got it?
是的
Yeah.
很好
Good.
我可指望你了
I'm counting on you.
没事吧?
早上好
德国 柏林
谢谢
是他! 抓住他!
请跟我走一趟
法国 巴黎
你好
先生 跟我走一趟
意大利 罗马
欢迎来到罗马
早上好 先生
你好 跟我过来 这边
好的 没问题
Yeah, sure.
我是德·里奥
Del Rio.
谢谢你回电话给我
Thanks for calling me back.
我们抓到第三个人了
We got the third guy.
非常感谢 我把交接犯罪分子文件发给你
Thanks very much. I'll send you the paper work with the transfer.
再见
Bye.
好的 三个都抓到了
女士们 先生们 飞机即将降落于巴黎戴高乐机场
Ladies and gentlemen, we're now beginning our descend to Paris-Charles de Gaulle.
女士 现在需要请您关闭电脑
Miss, I've to ask you to put away your computer now.
你该擦擦鼻子
You should wipe your nose.
- 什么?  - 可以给我一杯香槟吗?
- Excuse me?  - May I have a glass of champagne?
嗯 好的 当然
Um, yes, of course.
女士 您的香槟
Miss, your champagne.
谢谢
Thank you.
很抱歉打扰... 但是 你必须收起小桌板了
I'm very sorry but... uh, you really need to close your table now.
好的
Sure.
敬知识
To knowledge.
若它们的栖息之地不适合繁殖后代...
If the habitat is not sufficiently favorable or nurturing...
细胞会选择长生不老
the cell will choose immortality.
换句话来说 自给自足以及自主管理
In another word, self-sufficiency and self-management.
不 女士 女士
No, miss, miss.
您必须回到座椅上
You must remain seated.
女士 站住!
Miss, stop!
女士...
Miss...
女士 打开门! 您必须回到您的座椅上! 女士!
Miss, open the door! You really have to go back to your seat! Miss!
我们马上要降落了 请您开门!
We're going to land soon, please, open the door!
说话啊 您还好吗?
Please, say something, are you okay?
女士?
Miss?
女士!
Miss!
女士 请开门!
Miss, please open the door!
快帮忙 帮我打开!
Do something, help me open!
回答我! 开门!
Answer me! Open the door!
女士? 您还好吗? 说句话啊!
Miss? Are you okay? Say something!
她小腹有伤疤?
是的 是我们给她取出来的
- 她还好吗?  - 很好 她没事
我给她注射了一针 她一天内会醒过来
- 医生 她醒了  - 你确定?
是的 她坐在床上
就是她
- 你没铐住她?  - 必须有啊!
女士 不要动!
Miss, don't move!
- 我要跟你单独谈谈  - 我要你举起双手
- I need to talk to you alone.  - And I need you to put your hands up, please.
你拿到那几袋东西了吗?
Did you get the packets?
是的
Yes.
- 在哪里?  - 一个安全的地方
- Where're they?  - They're safe.
就在巴黎
Here, in Paris.
交给我更安全
They'll be safer in my hands.
别把车放那里 停好了
你知道 作为警察 怪事我见过一些
You know, as a cop, we see some pretty weird shit
可是坦白地说
but I've to be honest with you.
你刚在那的举动 把我吓坏了
What you did back there, that freaked me out.
让所有人一下昏睡过去
To put everyone to sleep like that,
我该担心吗?
do I need to be worried?
不用
No.
好的
Good.
你介意吗?
Do you mind?
不介意
No.
- 这是什么?  - 韩语 我来开车
- What's that?  - Korean, I'm going to drive.
嘿! 嘿! 嘿! 不! 不! 不! 这是警车!
Hey! Hey! Hey! No! No! No! This is a police car!
你不能这么做! 不 不能这样 女士
You can't! No, this is not possible, lady.
这是警车!
This is a police car!
好的 好吧
OK, OK.
伙计们 进去!
先生 先生 很抱歉 先生
Sir, sir, excuse me, sir.
我有话要说
I need to talk to somebody.
和警察说去吧
听着 我是德国公民 我要见律师
Look, I'm a German citizen and I demand us a lawyer.
我看着手术
- 去弄点吃的来  - 你这个吃货
你平时都这么开车吗?
Do you always drive like that?
我以前没开过车
I never driven before.
真好
Great.
- 嘿 这是单行道!  - 我们要迟到了
- Hey, this is one way!  - We're late.
嘿 迟到总比没命好吧
Hey, I would rather be late than dead.
我们不会死的
We never really die.
抱歉 先生 我不同意...
Sorry, sir, I don't agree...
我没意见
I'm fine, fine.
我要告诉他们别跟着我们
I'm going to tell them to stop following us.
不用麻烦了
Don't bother.
嘿 我给你买了...
把箱子给我
Give me the case.
杀了她 拿到毒品
别傻站着 杀了她!
打开
Open it.
我们走
Let's go.
我觉得我什么都帮不到你
I'm not sure I could be of any help for you.
不 你帮得到
Yes, you are.
怎么帮?
What for?
提醒我
A reminder.
可以走了吗?
Shall we go?
我们去哪里?
Where are we going?
第一个路口左转
Take the first left.
好的
Okay.
跟上那辆车
- 教授?  - 谢谢
- Professor?  - Thanks.
- 你好?  - 我是露西
- Yes?  - Lucy.
是她 她打来了
It's her, it's her.
嘿 你好 你在巴黎?
Hey you, you're in Paris?
是的 我到了
Yes, I'm.
很好 很好 太好了
Good, good, excellant.
听着 我已经离开酒店了 来大学里了
So, look, I'm no longer at the hotel now, uh, I've come to the university
我已经请来几位同事一起讨论你的事情了
where I've taken the liberty of calling and gathering a few of my colleagues to discuss your case.
他们都是各自领域的精英... 可以信赖
Top men in their field and um... very trustworthy.
我相信你
I trust you.
噢 谢谢 那我们可以在学校见吗?
Oh, thank you. So, do you think you can meet us here at the university?
我... 我很高兴见到你
I'm, uh...I'm very pleased to meet you.
我也是
Likewise.
- 我是德·里奥警长  - 你好
- Captain Del Rio.  - How do you do?
我... 介绍同事给你认识
Let... let me introduce you to my colleagues.
这位是卡帝亚教授 脑外科医生
This is Professor Cartier, neuro surgeon.
- 教授...  - 所有人我都认识
- Professor...  - I know who everyone is.
啊 当然
Ah, of course.
嗯 先生们 这位是露西 第一个女人...
Uh, gentlemen, this is Lucy, the first woman to...
我想说... 我之前有介绍...
I mean... like I mentioned earlier...
露西小姐 因为某种对我来说还是个迷的原因
Ms. Lucy has for reasons, remains a mystery to me,
她脑部的某些区域得到开发
unlocked certain portion of her brain
可以进入
that offered access
我们... 未知的某些领域
to... previously unexplored celebral zones.
她有超能力
She has abilities.
能给我们示范下吗?
Can you give us an example?
你的女儿 盖布里埃尔 六岁时死于车祸
Your daughter, Gabriel, aged 6, died in a car accident.
是辆蓝色轿车 皮座椅...
It was a blue car, leather seats...
后视镜上有只塑料小鸟挂饰
plastic bird hanging from the rear view mirror.
老大 我们有五个人死在医院 对不起
还剩多少人手?
我这边还有二十五人
该死的 她真顽强 她是个巫婆
我知道
我要亲手杀了她
有人要来了 你能守住这里吗?
There're men coming here, can you secure the room?
- 我需要集中注意力  - 好的
- I need to stay focus.  - Sure.
快点
Speed it up.
你如何掌握这些信息的?
How did you manage to access all these information?
电子脉冲...
Electrical impulses...
每个细胞都熟悉其他的细胞 并且相互交流
Every cell knows and talks to every other cell.
彼此间每秒钟交换一千比特信息
They exchange a thousand bits of information between them per second.
细胞们聚在一起 形成强大的通信网
Cells group together, forming a giant web of communication
然后构成物质
which in turn forms matter.
细胞们聚在一起 组成形态
Cells get together, take on one form,
变形 再重新组合
deform, reform,
本质上没什么不同 都是一样的
makes no difference, it's all the same.
人类认为自己独一无二
Human considers themself unique.
所以他们将人类存在的所有理论都植根于独特上
So, they rooted their whole theory of existence on their uniqueness.
"一"... 是衡量一切的标准 但其实不是
"One"... is the unit of measure but it's not.
所有的社交系统不过只是"草图"
All social systems we put into place are mere "sketch".
一加一等于二 这是我们唯一知道的
1 + 1 = 2 That's all we learned.
但一加一从来就不等于二
But 1 + 1 has never equalled 2.
事实上 没有所谓的数字或字母
They're in fact, no numbers and no letters.
我们把自己的存在用人类的概念去解释
We codify our existence to bring it down to human size
以便理解
to make it comprehensible.
我们创造了尺度 忘记其实一切变幻莫测
We created the scale so that we can forget its unfathomable scale.
但如果人类不是衡量的标尺
But if humans are not the unit of measure,
世界也不是由数学原理掌控的
and the world isn't governed by mathemathical laws,
谁来掌控一切?
what governs all that?
一辆车驶过路面...
Form a car speeding down the road...
加速这幅画面无穷快
speed up the image infinitely
车辆消失
and the car disappears.
所以 什么证明了我们的存在?
So, what proof do we have of its existence?
时间给我们存在合法性
Time gives legitimacy to its existence.
时间是衡量一切的标准
Time is the only true unit of meassure.
它证明物质的存在
It gives proof to the existence of matter.
没有时间
Without time,
我们都不存在
we don't exist.
时间才是"个体"
Time is "unity".
给我搜整个大楼 找到她!
我们撑不了太久的
We wouldn't be able to hold them for much longer.
那开始吧
Time to go then.
你确定要这么大剂量?
Are you sure you need such huge doses?
我怕你承受不了
I'm afraid you won't survive.
我身体里的一些细胞会誓死捍卫它们的完整性
Some cells inside me will fight and defend their integrity to the very end.
为了开发最后一部分 我必须逼迫它们
In order to attain the last few percent, I've to force it.
击破细胞 打开细胞核
To crack the cells open to their nucleus.
这些知识 露西...
All these knowledge, Lucy...
我甚至不确定人类能否接受
I'm not even sure that mankind is ready for it.
我们被权势利益所驱使
We're so driven by power and profit.
鉴于人类本性
Given man's nature,
也许这只会给我们带来动荡和混乱
it might bring us only instability and chaos.
无知才导致混乱 不是知识
Ignorance brings chaos, not knowledge.
我会造一个电脑 把我所知的一切放在里面
I'll build a computer and download all my knowledge in it.
我会想办法把它给你
I'll find a way for you to have access to it.
好的
Yeah.
我希望你的牺牲是值得的
I just hope, we'll be worthy of your sacrifice.
不准动!
Nobody move!
能听懂英语吗?
Do you understand English?
她在干吗?
What is she doing?
她在寻找能量和物质
She's looking for energy and matter.
还在尝试连接我们的电脑
And she's trying to connect with our computers.
冲俊!
我在这里 老大!
干掉他们
好的 老大!
你们 给我上
好了吗?
你还好吗?
快找医生 快!
天啊 怎么回事?
Oh my God, what's happening?
她在做什么?
What's she making?
我猜是新一代的计算机
A new generation of computer, I presume.
她呢?
她人呢?
回答我!
嘿 说你呢!
Hey, you!
看电脑 它在移动
Look, the computer, it's moving.
嘿
Hey.
她去哪里了?
Where is she?
我无处不在
十亿年前 我们被赐予了生命
Life was given to us a billion years ago.
现在你知道能用它做什么了
Now you know what to do with it.
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: 雷丘 滢小歪 咳嗽的小鱼
校对: 浅陷夜蓝 影子